* ### DASH
    
* ### Commuter Express
    
    * [409 to Civic Center
        
        A.M. to E. Glendale​/​Downtown
        
        P.M. to Glendale​/​Montrose​/​Tujunga​/​Sunland​/​Lake View Terrace​/​Sylmar](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/409/409.html)
    * [419 to Downtown
        
        A.M. to Downtown Los Angeles
        
        P.M. to Chatsworth](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/419/419.html)
    * [423 to Downtown
        
        A.M. to Downtown​/​USC
        
        P.M. to LADOT Encino P&R​/​Calabasas &​/​OR Agoura Hills​/​Thousand Oaks](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/423/423.html)
    * [431 to Financial District
        
        A.M. to Downtown
        
        P.M. to Westwood](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/431/431.html)
    * [437 to Financial District
        
        A.M. to Downtown
        
        P.M. to Culver City​/​Marina Del Rey​/​Venice](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/437/437.html)
    * [438 to Financial District
        
        A.M. to Downtown
        
        P.M. to Redondo Beach](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/438/438.html)
    * [439 to El Segundo
        
        A.M. to El Segundo
        
        P.M. to Downtown](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/439/439.html)
    * [448 to Financial District
        
        A.M. to Downtown
        
        P.M. to Rancho Palos Verdes](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/448/448.html)
    * [142
        
        Westbound to Ports O'Call & Sampson
        
        Eastbound to Long Beach Transit Gallery](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/142/142.html)
    * [422
        
        A.M. to Hollywood​/​San Fernando Valley​/​Agoura Hills​/​Thousand Oaks
        
        P.M. to San Fernando Valley​/​Hollywood​/​Downtown](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/422/422.html)
    * [534
        
        A.M. to West Los Angeles
        
        P.M. to Downtown](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/534/534.html)
    * [549
        
        Eastbound to Burbank​/​Glendale​/​Pasadena
        
        Westbound to Glendale​/​Burbank​/​Encino](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/549/549.html)
    * [573
        
        Southbound to Westwood​/​Century City
        
        Northbound to Encino​/​Mission Hills](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/573/573.html)
    * [574
        
        Southbound to LAX​/​El Segundo
        
        Northbound to Encino​/​Granada Hills](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/574/574.html)
    * [Union Station​/​Bunker Hill Shuttle
        
        Union Station​/​Bunker Hill](https://www.ladottransit.com/comexp/routes/usbunkerhill/usbunkerhill.html)
* ### Cityride
    
* ### LA_now_
    
* ### Other Services
    
* ### Rider Alerts
    
* ### How to Ride
    
* ### Accessibility
    
* ### About Us
    
    * [Disadvantaged Business Enterprise (DBE) Three-Year Overall Goal for Federal Fiscal Years 2025-2027](https://www.ladottransit.com/dbe)

back

City of Los Angeles Department of Transportation Privacy Policy
===============================================================

_Modified: December 2023_

LADOT Transit understands that safeguarding the privacy of the personal information of its riders is crucial to their loyalty. This policy will provide the users of LADOT Transit's DASH, Commuter Express, Cityride and LAnow services with details on how we collect, manage, use, disclose, delete, and secure personal information you provide to us when using our services, website, mobile applications, email notifications or applying for reduced fare, paratransit or other services that require a User to provide personal information. LADOT Transit does not deploy any automated decision-making technology. This policy conforms to the California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA) that mandates that consumers have the right to be informed of how their data may be collected and used.

### Your Privacy and the Type of Information LADOT Transit Collects

As a user of our services, you may provide us with information voluntarily when you use our website, use our mobile applications, apply for a reduced fare or for Cityride or LAnow services. That Personal Information you provide to us voluntarily could include:

* Name
* Address
* Email address
* Telephone number
* Credit/debit card information (LA Mobile and LAnow only)
* Birthdate
* GPS location (LA Mobile and LAnow only)
* Mobile device unique identifier (LA Mobile and LAnow only)

LADOT Transit and/or its third-party contractors, consultants and vendors connected with the operation of LADOT Transit services (Contractors) do not sell, rent, share, or disclose any Personal Information to outside sources in any way that is not described in this Policy without first obtaining your consent. All the Personal Information that a rider provides voluntarily is solely used to fulfill the rider’s request. LADOT Transit and its Contractors may disclose your Personal Information only when required by law or when the rider has approved such use, also known as opting in.  
Some features of the ladottransit.com website require the use of cookies. Cookies are data files stored on a User’s hard drive at the request of a website that enable the site to recognize users who previously visited the site retaining customer preferences and history. The only information a cookie can contain is the information that the User provides.

### Aggregated Information

LADOT Transit receives certain types of aggregated information that is used to improve LADOT Transit’s website, online services, and mobile applications. LADOT Transit uses Google Analytics to compile usage information for ladottransit.com. Google Analytics captures a user’s IP address and the page URL that the User is visiting. The IP address is a unique set of numbers assigned to a User’s computer by the User’s internet service provider. That address is logged automatically by the LADOT Transit contractor’s server whenever a User visits ladottransit.com as well as the tie of the visit and the pages that were visited. This aggregate data helps LADOT Transit to better understand how its customers use its website and to leverage that data to improve the user experience. Some LADOT Transit applications as well as its real time bus information system use Global Positioning System technology to identify the User’s location in order to provide specific information that is requested by the User. If a User sends email to LADOT Transit that includes Personally Identifiable Information, LADOT Transit only uses that email address to respond to the User’s message. If necessary, LADOT Transit may forward the User’s email to a peer agency or contractor if LADOT Transit cannot answer the User’s request directly. LADOT Transit does not provide User email addresses or sell email addresses to third parties for commercial purposes.

### Third Parties

The LADOT Transit website, ladottransit.com, and its mobile applications are provided and maintained by third-party Contractors. LADOT Transit and/or its third-party contractors, consultants and vendors utilize User Information solely for purposes of providing service on ladottransit.com and LADOT Transit applications.

### Public Records Act

LADOT Transit is a bureau of the City of Los Angeles Department of Transportation. As a result, LADOT Transit is subject to public records laws of the State of California, specifically the California Public Records Act ftc.ca.gov and the City of Los Angeles Government Code Section 6253(c) lacity.gov/directory. Any information contained on or submitted to LADOT Transit’s website, its mobile applications and its service requirements may be subject to disclosure pursuant to the Public Records Act and Code Section 6253 (c). Users should not provide Personal Information if you are concerned about disclosure of your information under that Act or the City Code referenced above.

### Security and Safeguards

LADOT Transit’s Contractors monitor its website as well as its mobile applications to identify attempts to gain access to information. Every commercially reasonable effort is used to secure your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure by using appropriate safeguards to protect the ladottransit.com website and our mobile applications. Please be aware, however, despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Due to the nature of internet communications and evolving technologies, we cannot provide, and disclaim, assurance that the information you provide to us will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by intruders who obtain unauthorized access. If we detect an intrusion or other unauthorized access to or use of Personal Information, we will use reasonable efforts to notify the individual(s) whose Personal Information has been compromised.

LADOT Transit will only retain Personal Information for as long as it is required or until such time as you determine you no longer wish to be provided with information regarding LADOT Transit services. LADOT Transit will delete Personal Information from its records when the information is no longer required or when you direct us in writing to remove your Personal Information from our databases.

### Consent

By using the ladottransit.com website, one of LADOT Transit’s mobile applications or providing information for a reduced fare or paratransit program, the rider consents to the use of the Personal Information required and acknowledges understanding of this policy.

### Questions and Comments

LADOT Transit is committed to adhering to this Policy and to protecting the privacy of its riders. We welcome your comments, suggestions and questions:

**LADOT Customer Service Center**  
201 North Los Angeles Street, #16  
Los Angeles, California 90012

or
